since this is about forgiveness that
因为这是关于宽恕的
obviously overlaps with the area of
显然与地区重叠
conflicts so I've got a conflict
冲突所以我发生了冲突
resolution joke to start off with
分辨率笑话开始
doesn't that sound weird a conflict
冲突听起来不是很奇怪
resolution joke when I go to do
当我去做时，决定开玩笑
mediations and church interventions and
调解和教会干预和
things like that I can't tell this joke
这样的事情，我不能说这个笑话
it's not appropriate so I can only do it
它不合适， 所以我只能这样做
at conferences like this there was a guy
在会议上这样有一个家伙
that was stuck on an island by himself
那个被自己困在岛上的人
and he was finally rescued I'm giving
他终于获救了我正在给予他
you the nickel version joke I could
你可以用镍版笑话
really expand this thing out and he was
真的把这件事扩大了，他就是
finally discovered on this island and
终于发现在这个岛上和
when they found him on the island they
当他们在岛上发现他们时
were really impressed with all the
真的打动了 所有
buildings on the island that he had
他拥有的岛上的建筑物
built so they said so what's that and he
建成所以他们说那是什么，他
said oh that's my house and they said
哦，那是我的房子，他们说
that's beautiful and they said well that
这很美，他们说得很好
building over there with the cross on it
在那边建造十字架
that must be your church he said but
他说 ，那一定是你的教会
what's that one over there with the
什么是一个在那里与
cross on and he said oh that's where I
交叉，他说哦，那就是我
used to go to church
以前去教堂
where'd you like that so we can't even
你喜欢哪里，所以我们甚至不能
get along with ourselves can we over the
与我们相处可以我们过去
last few years this is one of my
最近几年这是我的一个
favorite topics because over the last
最喜欢的话题，因为过去
few years I've been doing quite a few
几年来我一直在做很多事情
mediations and it is wonderful to sit in
调解，坐在里面很棒
a mediation room and watch people get
一个调解室，看着人们得到
reconciled with one another I get I
彼此和好，我得到了我
think I get a bigger charge from that
我觉得我从中得到了更大的收费
than I do just more traditional biblical
比我更传统的圣经
counseling sitting in a room and helping
咨询坐在房间里帮助
people work through issues and see them
人们通过问题工作并看到它们
asking forgiveness of each other
请求彼此原谅
confessing sin it's what the core the
承认罪是它的核心
gospel is really about seeing mercy
福音真的是看到怜悯
given to each other
相互给予
willingness to serve one another and I
愿意和我一起服务
want to just give you a couple real
我想给你一些真实的
quick stories to start off with about
关于开始的快速故事
two years ago I was working with a
两年前我和一个人在一起工作
family and many people had told one
一家人和许多人告诉过一个人
person in this family it is absolutely
这个家庭中的人绝对是
impossible to be reconciled with that
不可能与之和解
type of person in fact two pastors had
实际上有两个牧师的人
told this young men and it was his
告诉这些年轻人，这是他的
potential father-in-law that they were
他们是潜在的岳父
referring to they said you just cannot
指的是他们说你不能
be reconciled to that type of man he is
和他那种类型的人和好了
a control freak there's just absolutely
一个控制狂，绝对是
no way to be reconciled to him so as I
就像我一样，没办法和他和好
was trying to get him ready for
我试图让他做好准备
mediation I was kind of going against
调解我有点反对
and having to work against two men who
并且不得不与两个男人一起工作
are my fellow ministers and they were
是我的部长们，他们是
telling him he would come and listen to
告诉他他会来听
me and I'm having him read a book like
我，我让他读一本像这样的书
the peacemaker and they're saying don't
和平缔造者， 他们说不
even go in there you're crazy if you go
即使去那里，如果你去，你也会疯狂
back into that meeting go to a mediation
回到那次会议去调解
room well he took a big risk and he
房间很好，他冒了很大的风险，他
decided to follow through with the
决定与坚持到底
mediation I had set aside a Friday
调解我已经预定了星期五
evening and most of the day Saturday for
晚上和周六的大部分时间
this mediation to take place he walked
此中介要发生，他走了
in and he took Matthew seven seriously
在他和他认真对待马修七
of get the log out of your own eye and
从你自己的眼睛中获取日志
we have people work on what are the
我们有人在做什么工作
things that you've done to contribute to
的事情，你对我所做的贡献
this conflict he took that homework
他接受了这项冲突
assignment very seriously and he came
任务非常认真，他来了
into the mediation room and even though
进入调解室，尽管如此
I had this whole agenda that we followed
我有我们遵循的整个议程
a run of mediation he kind of hijacked
他被劫持的一系列调解
it and he started confessing almost from
它和他几乎开始承认
the very first minute we were done with
我们完成的第一分钟
the mediation in about three hours I
大约三个小时的调解我
walked into the door that Friday evening
星期五晚上走进门口
one of the only times in 30 years of
30年来唯一的一次
ministry that I was home early from a
我早就回家了
meeting and my wife said she was just
会议和我的妻子说她只是
kind of shocked and she said what
有点震惊，她说什么
happened and I said I just saw a miracle
发生了，我说我刚看到一个奇迹
I saw a wonderful reconciliation take
我看到了精彩的和解
place as there was confession of sin and
因为有罪和忏悔的地方
forgiveness just this past spring the
在过去的春天，宽恕了
Lord blessed us with a trip to Europe
主赐给我们一趟欧洲之旅
and I was teaching in Switzerland so I
我在瑞士教书，所以我
was suffering for Jesus and Switzerland
为耶稣和瑞士苦难
every day my wife and I would look out
每天我的妻子和我都会注意
the bedroom window and the Alps were
卧室的窗户和阿尔卑斯山
just a few miles away and I was doing a
在几英里之外，我正在做一个
conflict resolution conference for a
为解决冲突的会议
mission agency there I didn't realize
任务机构那里我没有意识到
that I was walking into the middle of a
我是走进 的中间
conflict between missionaries so I was
传教士之间的冲突让我如此
teaching on conflict resolution and the
关于解决冲突和教育的教学
first day I was there I was teaching
第一天，我在那儿教书
conflict resolution principles and I
冲突解决原则和我
started hearing word and little murmurs
开始听到单词和小杂音
about we've got some missionaries in
关于我们有一些传教士
conflict and they've been in conflict
冲突，他们一直在冲突
with each other over a year and then the
相互超过一年，然后是
next day I heard a little bit more and
第二天，我听到更多的一点点 ，
then by the end of that second day one
然后在第二天结束时
of the parties came to me and started
各方来到我面前并开始了
talking to me about what was going on by
跟我谈的是 怎么回事
the beginning of the third day two more
第三天开始两点多了
people came and started talking to me
人们来了，开始跟我说话
what about what was going on and what it
那是怎么回事，怎么回事
all worked out to was that by the end of
所有的努力都是到了最后
the week we ended up having a mediation
我们最后进行调解的那一周
and it worked out incredibly well
它的效果令人难以置信
because they were getting hammered with
因为他们受到了重创
biblical counseling conflict resolution
圣经咨询冲突解决
principles during the day or during the
在白天或在原则
morning and then in the afternoon we
早上再到下午我们
were having counseling sessions
有咨询会议
Wednesday and Thursday to get them ready
周三和周四让他们准备好
for the mediation and then Friday after
为调解，然后星期五之后
the morning session we started meeting
早上我们开始开会
Friday afternoon and went into the
星期五下午进入了
evening and what had been a
晚上和过去的一切
conflict that had been over a year going
冲突已经超过一年去
on causing turmoil and the the team
引起混乱和团队
there in Europe they there was
他们在欧洲那里
confession of sin there was forgiveness
承认犯罪是宽恕
we had about eight different issues we
我们有八个不同的问题
had to work through where there had been
不得不在那里工作
friction with one another we worked
彼此摩擦我们工作
through those issues they confess their
通过这些问题， 他们承认了他们的
sin to one another they asked the
彼此犯罪， 他们问道
granted forgiveness to one another the
得到了彼此的宽恕
rest of the team kind of knew the rest
其余的团队知道其余的
of the missionaries kind of knew what
传教士有点知道什么
was going on but they were meeting
正在进行，但他们正在开会
upstairs for their last session on
楼上的最后一次会议
Friday night and we wrapped up our
星期五晚上我们结束了我们的
mediation we went upstairs and they were
调解我们上楼，他们是
having communion together and in the
共融和共融
middle of the communion service I kind
中间的圣餐服务我很善良
of gave the thumbs up I gave the thumbs
我竖起了大拇指
up signal to the director of the mission
向任务主任发出信号
agency that was there and he knew that
在那里的代理商，他知道这一点
that meant that things had gone well
这意味着事情进展顺利
because he was kind of waiting word on
因为他有点等待
had things going well or not and he
他的事情进展顺利
asked us to give some testimonies and
要求我们提供一些证词和
the parties that had been in conflict
冲突各方
with each other gave public testimony to
与对方公开作证
their fellow missionaries of being
被他们的同胞传教士
reconciled with one another and then it
彼此和解，然后它
was just so perfect we finished the
真是太完美我们完成了
whole thing with communion together
共融的整个事物
worshiping the Lord together what we're
一起敬拜主 ，我们是什么
gonna finish with today is the subject
今天要完成的是主题
of forgiveness I'm gonna try to talk in
宽恕我会试着谈谈
high gear here as we go through the
我们经历过这里的高速档
notes mm-hmm and we're going to examine
注意mm-hmm，我们要检查
some incredible passages of scripture
一些令人难以置信的经文段落
scripture like Ephesians 4:31 and 32
像以弗所书4:31和32一样的经文
because of the gospel I believe
因为福音，我相信
Christians are capable of superhuman
基督徒有超人的能力
acts of forgiveness I'm gonna say it
宽恕的行为我会说的
again just for the sake of emphasis
再次只是为了强调
because of the gospel I believe
因为福音，我相信
Christians are capable of superhuman
基督徒有超人的能力
acts of forgiveness John MacArthur in
宽恕行为John MacArthur in
his book the freedom and power of
他的书中的自由和力量
forgiveness tells this little story he
宽恕告诉他这个小故事
said my own brother-in-law went to a
说我自己的姐夫去了
jail to express his forgiveness and
监狱表达他的宽恕和
offer the forgiveness of God to the drug
向毒品提供上帝的宽恕
addict who had murdered his son in a
在一个人中谋杀了他儿子的瘾君子
market holdup something like that is
市场敲竹杠类似的东西是
only possible
只有可能
because of the gospel Ephesians 4:31 and
因为福音以弗所书4:31和
32 say let all bitterness and wrath and
32说让所有的苦涩和愤怒
anger and clamor and slander and be put
愤怒，喧嚣和诽谤，并被放
away from you along with all malice and
远离你和所有的恶意和恶意
be kind to one another tender-hearted
善待彼此多情
forgiving each other just as God in
彼此饶恕，正如神
Christ also has forgiven you here's
基督也在这里饶恕了你
here's what I'd like to do I'd like to
这里是我想要做的 ，我想什么
look at the context of the book so turn
看看这本书的背景，转过来
with me to Ephesians 1 if you would
如果你愿意，和我一起去以弗所书1
Ephesians chapter 1 and I'm gonna pick
以弗所书第1章，我要选
out some verses to give us a little bit
一些经文给我们一点点
of the flavor of Ephesians if you were
如果你是以弗所人的味道
to summarize the book of Ephesians I
总结以弗所书I
would summarize it something like this
会总结它是 这样 的
first three chapters Christ is the head
前三章基督是头
of his body the church first last three
他的身体教堂最后三个
chapters now live like it so the first
章节现在像第一个一样生活
three chapters doctrine the last three
三章学说最后三章
chapters daily first three chapters your
每日章节前三章你的章节
position in Christ last two three
在基督的位置最后两三
chapters practicing your position in
实践你的职位的章节
Christ
基督
how has the gospel impacted us chapters
福音如何影响我们的章节
1 2 3 theologically now how does the
1 2 3神学现在怎么样了
gospel impact you and your relationships
福音影响你和你的人际关系
with others and realize chapters 4 to 6
与他人一起实现第4至第6章
are just saturated with others it's
只是满足于其他人
about relationships chapters 4 5 and 6
关于第4章5和第6 章的关系
are just saturated with relationships in
只是饱和了人际关系
the church and how does Christ being the
教会以及基督是怎样的
head of his church impact our
他教会冲击 头 我们
relationships with one another
彼此之间的关系
so chapter 1 he says this and I'm gonna
所以第一章他说这个，我要去
read verses 3 through 8 and I already
阅读第3到第8节，我已经
referred to this earlier but notice all
提到这个较早，但发现所有
the things that God has done for us in
上帝为我们所做的事
Christ and these are done God says
上帝说，基督和这些都是完成的
they're done they're reality
他们完成了他们是现实
verse 3 blessed be the God and father of
第3节祝福归与父亲
our Lord Jesus Christ who has blessed us
我们的主耶稣基督谁曾赐给我们
with spiritual blessing in the heavenly
在天上有属灵的祝福
places in Christ just as he chose us in
就像他选择我们一样， 在基督 里
him before the foundation of the world
他在世界建立之前
that we should be holy and blameless
我们应该是圣洁和无可指责的
before him in love he predestined us to
在他恋爱之前，他注定了我们
adoption as sons through Jesus Christ
通过耶稣基督成为儿子
to himself according to the kind
根据种类对自己
intention of his will to the praise of
他的意志意图得到了赞美
the glory of His grace which he freely
他恩典的荣耀，他自由
bestowed on us in the beloved one in him
在他心爱的人身上赐予我们
we have redemption through his blood the
我们通过血液救赎了
forgiveness of our trespasses according
根据我们的过失宽恕
to the riches of His grace which he
以他丰富的恩典，他
lavished upon us and I'll stop right
在我们身上慷慨解囊，我会停下来
there I'll make the same statement that
那里我会做出同样的声明
I did earlier that Ken Sandee makes and
我先前做肯让珊妮和
that is if Christians are the most
如果基督徒是最多的话
forgiving people in the world shouldn't
世界上原谅的人不应该
we be the most forgiving people in the
我们是在最宽容的人
world or another way we could say it is
世界或另一种方式，我们可以说这是
if we have been shown the most mercy in
如果我们被证明是最怜悯的
the world shouldn't we be the most
世界不应该是我们最多的
merciful people in the world or if we've
世界上仁慈的人，或者我们是谁
been shown the most grace in the world
被证明是世界上最优雅的
shouldn't we be the most gracious people
我们不应该是最仁慈的人
in the world notice the the words that
在世界上注意到那些话
are used here and keep the context in
在这里使用 并保持上下文
mind again Christ is the head of his
再想一想基督是他的头
body the church this is what he has done
教会这是他所做的
for you as the head of his church and
因为你作为他教会的领导和
now who you are in him now chapters 4 to
现在你在他身边的人现在是第4章到第4章
6 how do you live this relationship with
6 你是如何与这种关系生活的？
others as if you're really connected to
其他人好像你真的联系在一起
Christ well it's the same way he gave
基督很好，就像他给的一样
you lavish grace now you give each other
你慷慨的恩惠，现在你互相给予
lavish grace he gave you abundant mercy
他给你丰富的怜悯
now you give each other abundant mercy
现在你给对方充分的怜悯
he gave you this incredible forgiveness
他给了你这种令人难以置信的宽恕
in Christ
在基督里
now you grant incredible forgiveness to
现在你给予了令人难以置信的宽恕
each other in Christ if Christians are
如果基督徒是在基督里彼此
the most forgiving people in the world
最宽容的人在世界上
we ought to be the most forgiving so
我们应该是最宽容的
let's go to or just think a little bit
让我们去或者只是思考一下
more theologically what's going on and
在神学上更多的是发生了什么
then we want to go to the immediate
然后我们想立刻去
context of Ephesians chapter 4
以弗所书第4章的背景
theologically what's going on biblically
神学上圣经上发生了什么
this is the big picture of Scripture we
这是我们圣经的大局
see it in Genesis 3 what happens at the
在创世纪3中看到它会发生什么
end of the story in Genesis 3 they're
在创世纪3中他们的故事结束了
out of the Garden fellowship with God is
出于与上帝的花园团契是
broken theologically what's going on is
在神学上打破了正在发生的事情
that the major penalty of sin is
罪的主要惩罚是
separation from our God it is
它与我们的上帝分离
forgiveness in Jesus Christ that
耶稣基督的宽恕
releases us from this penalty that isn't
释放我们免受这种惩罚
it great that we're ending this
我们结束这件事真是太好了
conference these 10 hours with the
会议这10个小时与
gospel I think that's an absolutely
福音我认为这是绝对的
wonderful way for us to end this
我们结束这个的好方法
conference is to get leave here
会议是要离开这里
reveling rejoicing in the gospel and the
在福音和福音里欢喜快乐
forgiveness that we have in the Lord I
宽恕，我们在我主
think John Piper puts it well when he
认为约翰·派博说得好时，他
says that the gospel the cross is not
说十字架的福音不是
the end the cross is the means to the
十字架是结束的手段
end the message of the gospel is the
结束消息的福音是
means to the end here's what he means by
意味着到最后这里是他的意思是什么
that the message of the gospel was meant
该福音的信息是指
for the end result of reconciling us to
为调和我们的最终结果
God we were created we were made for
上帝， 我们被创造了我们为之而生
relationship with the creator Genesis 1
与创作者Genesis 1的关系
and 2 Genesis 3 this horrible thing
和2创世记3这个可怕的事情
called sin comes and separates us from
被称为罪恶来自我们
our Creator and then the rest of the
我们的创造者，然后其余的
Bible is the story of redemption how the
圣经是 救赎 的故事
Lord is restoring us reconciling us to
主正在恢复我们和好我们
relationship with himself
与自己的关系
Ephesians 2:13 says it this way but now
以弗所书2:13这样说， 但现在
in Christ Jesus you who were formerly
在基督耶稣里你以前是谁
far off have been brought near by the
很远的地方已经被附近了
blood amen
血液阿门
now let's look at the immediate context
现在让我们来看看当前的背景
so let's go back to chapter 4 and think
让我们回到第4章并思考
immediate context and I'm going to come
直接的背景，我要来了
back to that Jeremiah 31 verse there in
回到那里的耶利米书31节
a moment that's an absolutely crucial
这一刻绝对至关重要
verse so let's come back in just a
诗那么，让我们回来 只是一个
moment immediate context in the
时刻的直接背景
immediate context he's now in the
眼前的情况他现在在
practical relationships of how does the
实际关系如何
gospel how does Christ being the head of
福音如何成为基督的头
his church impact the way we relate to
他的教会影响我们的关系
one another
另一个
earlier today I read the verse verses 1
今天早些时候我读了第1节经文
to 3 about those character traits
3关于这些性格特征
because we're walking in a manner worthy
因为我们走的路是值得的
of the calling with which we've been
我们去过的电话
called I've just explained to you what
叫我刚刚向你解释了什么
is the calling with which we've been
是我们过去的召唤
called we're part of the body of Christ
我们称自己是基督身体的一部分
he's the head of his body the church so
他是 教会的主体， 所以
how do we live up to the calling with
我们如何不辜负召唤
which we've been called later on in the
我们后来被称为
chapter
章节
starting with verse 20 he says you did
从第20节开始，他说你做到了
not learn Christ in this way he had just
他没有以这种方式学习基督
talked about the old Gentile life the
谈到了老外邦人的生活
pagan life that we've left behind he
异教徒的生活，我们留下了他
says you did not learn Christ in this
说你没有在这里学习基督
way if indeed you've heard him and have
如果确实你已经听过他的话
been taught in him just as truth is in
就像真相一样，在他里面受过教导
Jesus
耶稣
that you learn to lay aside the old self
你学会放下旧的自我
which is being corrupted in accordance
正在被破坏的
with the lusts of deceit and that you be
与欺骗的欲望和你是
renewed in the spirit of your mind and
以你的思想和精神更新
that you put on the new self which in
你穿上新的自这
the likeness of God has been created in
神的形像已经被创建
righteousness and holiness of truth put
真理的正义和圣洁
off be renewed put on repentance is
悔改的更新是
taking place in our lives progressive
发生在我们的生活中
sanctification is taking place in our
成圣正在我们的身上发生
lives as we put off we be renewed we are
我们推迟生活，我们正在更新
being renewed and we put on the new man
正在更新，我们穿上新人
now here's what Paul does he gives
现在这就是保罗所给予的
examples of what does this put off be
这个推迟的例子是什么
renewed and put on process look like
更新并加工过程看起来像
look at verse 28 for example most of
以大多数的例子来看28节
them have to do with relationships and a
他们有关系，一个 做
lot of them have to do with
很多人都 与
communication actually but here's one
实际上是沟通， 但这里是一个
about stealing there's a put off there's
关于窃取那里有一个推迟
a be renewed and there's a put-on
一个被更新，并有一个放式
there's things to stop there's things to
有事情可以阻止那些事情发生
do and then there's motives to change
做，然后有改变的动机
desires to change when he says be
希望在他说的时候改变
renewed and the spirit of the mind this
更新和心灵的精神
we'll talk more about this next month
我们下个月会谈到这个
he's not saying memorized the Bible and
他并不是说记住圣经和
you'll change I wish it was that easy
你会改变我希望它很容易
he's saying be renewed be being renewed
他说要续约续约
in the inner person of your intentions
在 你内心的人的意图
the mind is a synonym for the heart the
心灵是对心脏的同义词
more cognitive part of the heart but be
心脏的更多的认知一部分，但要
being renewed in the inner person of
正在更新中的内部人
your intentions your desires look at it
你的意图你的愿望看着它
in verse 28 there's definitely a put off
在第28节中，肯定有一个推迟
let him who steals steal no longer
让他抢断的人不再抢断
that's obviously to put off but rather
这显然是推迟而是
than rather let him labour performing
而不是让他劳动表演
with his hands what is good
用他的双手有什么好处
there's the put on so a thief needs to
这是小偷需要的
stop stealing start laboring this would
停止偷窃开始劳动这会
reform our prison system by the way Jay
以杰伊的方式改革我们的监狱系统
Adams asked the question decades ago how
亚当斯几十年前就问过这个问题
would you know when a thief is no longer
你知道什么时候不再是小偷吗？
a thief well you know a thief is no
小偷那么你知道贼是不
longer a thief when he's a hard-working
当他努力工作时，小偷更长
person who's learning to give to people
正在学习给人们的人
instead of take from people when you
而不是当你的人取走
know that they're utterly transformed by
知道他们完全被改造了
the power of the gospel so let him who
福音的功率，从而让他谁
steals steal no longer but rather
抢断不再是抢断
laborer performing with his hands what
劳动者用他的双手表演什么
is good now notice the change of motive
好现在注意到动机的变化
or the change of desire in order that he
或者为了他而改变欲望
may have something to share with him who
可能有什么东西可以与他分享
has need there's a put off there's a be
需要有一个推迟有一个
renewed and there's a put-on in each one
更新， 每个人都有一个装
of the illustrations that Paul gives so
保罗给出了这样的插图
that brings us right up to 31 and 32
这给我们带来了31和32
then in verses 31 and 32 he's giving the
然后在第31和32节他给出了
put off the be renewed and the put on
推迟更新和穿上
and he says let all bitterness and wrath
他说让所有的痛苦和愤怒
and anger and clamor and slander be put
和愤怒，喧嚣和诽谤
off from you along with all malice and
你和所有的恶意和恶意
be kind to one another tender-hearted
要善待彼此的温柔
forgiving each other there's the put on
相互饶恕有其他的东西
and now here's the change of motive the
现在这里是动机的变化了
be renewed in the spirit of your mind
以你的思想精神更新
just as God in Christ also has forgiven
就像在基督里的上帝也被宽恕一样
you that changes our intentions that
你改变了我们的意图
changes our our motives that's a new way
改变我们的动机，这是一种新的方式
of thinking that how can I withhold
想我怎么能扣留
forgiveness for you and from you when
宽恕你和你的时候
I've been forgiven so much in Christ Who
我在基督里得到了如此多的宽恕
am I to withhold forgiveness so
我在隐瞒宽恕等等
Christians can become capable of
基督徒可以变得有能力
superhuman acts of forgiveness the next
超人的宽恕行为是下一个
question then becomes what does it mean
那么问题就变成了它的意思
to forgive even as God for Christ's sake
为了基督的缘故，甚至为了原谅上帝
has forgiven us peacemaker ministries
我们原谅了和平缔造者的事工
and I'd like you to turn to Jeremiah 31
我希望你转向耶利米书31章
peacemaker ministries based upon this
基于此的和平制造者部委
theology of forgiveness has come up with
宽恕神学已经提出来了
what we call the four promises of
我们所说的四个承诺
forgiveness let's think through these
宽恕让我们思考这些
Paul just said forgive even as God for
保罗只是说原谅，即使是上帝
Christ's sake has forgiven us jeremiah
基督的缘故已经原谅了我们耶利米
31:34 says this this is the new covenant
31:34说这是新约
passage and it says this and they shall
通过，它说这个，他们应该
not teach again each man his neighbor
不再教导每个人他的邻居
and each man his brother saying know the
而他哥哥说的每个人都知道
Lord for they shall all know me from the
上帝，因为他们必都知道我从
least of them to the greatest of them
至少他们给他们最大的
declares the Lord for I will forgive
宣布主，我会原谅
their iniquity that word for iniquity
他们的罪孽是罪孽
means twisted nasarah version and their
意味着扭曲的nasarah版本和他们的
sin I will remember no more let's stop
罪恶我会记得不再让我们停下来
and ask ourselves a question
并问自己一个问题
their sin I will remember no more does
他们的罪我不会再记得了
God forget anything so God doesn't
上帝忘了什么，所以上帝没有
forget anything he's omniscient so this
忘记任何他无所不知的事情
can't mean that God goes into a brain
并不意味着上帝进入大脑
lapse in some way and forgets your sin
以某种方式失效并忘记你的罪
he chooses in Christ not to hold your
他在基督里选择不要抱你的
sin against you theologically you're
得罪你神学上你
doing the exact same thing when you
当你做同样的事情
choose to forgive someone because of
选择原谅某人因为
what God in Christ has done for you you
基督里的神为你做了 什么
grant forgiveness to the other person
给予对方宽恕
and you choose not to hold it against
而你选择不反对
them so we typically say it this way and
他们所以我们通常这样说
let me go back to that slide I will not
让我回到那个幻灯片我不会
dwell on this incident that means you're
详细说明这个事件意味着你
gonna have to fight when you've granted
当你被授予时，必须要战斗
forgiveness you're gonna have to fight
原谅你必须要战斗
with yourself not to dwell on it more
与自己不纠缠于它更多
about that a little bit I will not bring
关于一点点我也不会带来
this incident up and use it against you
这件事起来并用它来对付你
I will not talk to others about this
我不会和别人谈这件事
incident I will not allow this incident
事件我不会允许这件事
to stand between us or hinder our
站在我们之间或阻碍我们
personal relationship here's kind of an
个人关系在这里是一种
easy way to remember it and I use my
记住它的简单方法，我使用我的
fingers as pointers I'm not trying to
手指作为指针，我并不想
insult your intelligence but maybe it
侮辱你的智慧，但也许吧
quarter after five you need all the help
五分之一后你需要所有的帮助
you can get right so I will not dwell on
你可以做对，所以我不会再纠缠
it I'm not going to bring it up and use
它我不打算提起 并使用它
it against you I'm not going to talk to
它反对你我不打算和你 说话
others about this and I'm not going to
关于这一点的其他人，我不会这样做
allow this to stand between us that's
让它站在我们之间
the way you can remember the four
你记得四个人的方式
promises of forgiveness the directions
宽恕方向的承诺
that they're related to we even have a
他们与我们有关系甚至都有
way to teach this to children
教给孩子的方法
nice little rhyme here good thought hurt
好小韵在这里善良的想法伤害
you not gossip never friends forever how
你不是八卦永远不会永远的朋友如何
you like that our kids need to learn
你喜欢我们的孩子需要学习的东西
forgiveness too now let's think of the
宽恕现在让我们想一想
broader biblical teaching on forgiveness
关于宽恕的更广泛的圣经教导
this ought to thrill your heart it
这应该让你感到振奋
thrills mine over the last few weeks as
在过去的几个星期里，我惊慌失措
I've been going over this I've just been
我已经去了这一点，我刚去过的
reveling in the gospel again and what I
再次陶醉在福音里，我是什么
want to do is give you a brief
想做的就是给你简要介绍
introduction to three Greek words that
介绍三个希腊词
are used for forgiveness in the New
在新的用于宽恕
Testament
遗嘱
Afiya Meeker is oh my and Appa Luo they
AfiyaMeeker是我和他的Appa罗
give you different and
给你不一样的
on this idea of what does it mean to
关于它意味着什么的想法
forgive even as God for Christ's sake
为了基督的缘故，甚至原谅上帝
has forgiven you the first one apphia me
已经原谅了你的第一个apphia me
is also this will kind of twist your
也是这会扭曲你的
brain a little bit this one is used of
大脑有点用这个
divorce also it's translated divorce
离婚也是它的翻译离婚
because it means to send away so in
因为它意味着送走了
forgiveness
饶恕
I am sending something away what you're
我送你的东西
seeing here is we build up and we see
看到这里是我们建立起来，我们看到了
these three words and we combine them
这三个词我们将它们结合起来
all together is that we'll see that
总之，我们会看到这一点
forgiveness is not a feeling but
宽恕不是一种感觉而是
forgiveness is an act that is absolutely
宽恕绝对是一种行为
crucial to get across to count Solis
重要的是要算上Solis
because I can guarantee to you people
因为我可以保证你的人
aren't going to feel like forgiving you
不会感觉像原谅你
have to make a decision I will grant
我必须做出决定
forgiveness to someone based upon what
基于什么来宽恕某人
God in Christ has done for me
基督里的上帝为我做了
Afiya me there's one that you verse that
阿菲亚我有一个你这样说的
you're familiar with and it's that last
你很熟悉， 这就是最后一次
one if we confess our sins he is
一，如果我们承认他们的罪过他
faithful and just to forgive us of our
忠实而且只是原谅我们的
sins and cleanse us from all
所有人都 犯了罪，并洁净了我们
unrighteousness in that a beautiful
那个美丽的不义
verse I mean just absolutely comforting
我的意思是绝对安慰
God in Christ applies the forgiveness of
基督里的上帝应用了宽恕
Christ to you when you ask for
当你要求时，基督会给你
forgiveness when you confess your sins
当你承认自己的罪时，宽恕
there aren't feelings involved here this
有没有在这份涉及感情
is a judicial transaction that God makes
是上帝所做的司法交易
based upon what God in or what Christ
基于上帝在什么或什么基督
did for you
为你做了
Afiya me it's sent away this same word
阿菲亚我发了这个字
is used for you in mark 11:25 when it
在标记11:25时用于你
says whenever you stand praying so
每当你站起来祈祷时说
notice you're by yourself you're given a
注意你是你自己给了你一个
command forgive if you have anything
命令原谅，如果你有什么
against anyone so that your father in
反对任何人，以便你的父亲在
heaven will also forgive you your
天堂也会原谅你的
transgressions I'll make a quick comment
越狱我会做一个快速评论
about that last phrase in just a few
关于最后几个短语
minutes in heaven just so that your
在天堂的分钟只是让你的
father in heaven will also forgive you
天堂的父亲也会原谅你
your transgressions let's think about
你的过犯让我们思考一下
the second one courage oh my Colossians
第二个勇气哦我的歌罗西人
3:13 Corinne's oh my some of you if
3:13 Corinne噢，我的一些人，如果
you're familiar with greek at all you
你对所有人都很熟悉
recognize part of the word for grace in
认识到这个词的一部分是为了恩典
there this word has to do with
这个词与这个词有关
giving something graciously to pardon
请慷慨地给予赦免
graciously Corinne's oh my Colossians
慷慨的Corinne是我的歌罗西人
3:13 it's used two times and it says
3:13它被使用了两次，它说
bearing with one another and forgiving
彼此和宽容轴承
each other so pardon each other
彼此如此原谅对方
graciously whoever has a complaint
慷慨地抱怨谁
against anyone just as the Lord pardon
正如主赦免对任何人一样
you graciously forgave you
你慷慨地原谅了你
so should you Who am I to withhold
你也应该拒绝我
forgiveness when I've been given so much
我得到这么多的宽恕
forgiveness and I'll give you a
宽恕，我会给你一个
suggested homework assignment related to
建议的家庭作业相关
that in just a moment and then the last
只是片刻，然后是最后一刻
one is Appa Luo Appa Luo is used in Luke
一个是AppaLuoAppa Luo用于Luke
6:37 and it means to loose to set free
6:37这意味着松开以释放
set somebody free Luke 6:37 do not judge
设置有人自由路加福音6:37不要判断
and you will not be judged do not
而且你不会被评判
condemned and you will not be condemned
被谴责，你不会受到谴责
set them free pardon and you will be
让他们自由赦免，你会
pardoned so in your notes you see the
在你的笔记中赦免你看到了
principle forgiveness is not a feeling
宽恕原则不是一种感觉
nor forgetting or excusing it is a
也不会忘记或删除它
decision it is primarily an act of the
决定它主要是一个行为
will let's keep moving that brings up
将让我们继续前进
another important question and I'll just
另一个重要的问题，我只是
truthfully I'm gonna lay out the issue
说实话我会解决这个问题
for you here just over a couple of
对你来说， 只有几个
minutes and then you're gonna have to
分钟，然后你将不得不
make some decisions on your own because
自己做出一些决定因为
we have a difference of opinion a loving
我们有一种不同的意见
difference of opinion in the biblical
圣经中的意见分歧
counseling world on on this issue
在这个问题上为世界提供咨询
some teach that it's possible even for
有人教导它甚至可能
big transgressions big sins against you
大罪过你的大罪
you can unilaterally forgive meaning
你可以单方面原谅意义
forgiveness can be given just one
宽恕只能给一个人
direction but Jay Adams who is the
方向但杰伊亚当斯是谁
granddaddy of the biblical counseling
圣经辅导的爷爷
movement who we love and respect very
我们热爱和尊重的运动
much says that forgiveness can only be
很多人说宽恕只能是
granted if a person repents first of all
如果一个人首先悔改，则被授予
really it boils down to two main people
真正把它归结为两个主要的 人
taking different positions and one is
采取不同的立场，一个是
John MacArthur and the others Jay Adams
John MacArthur和其他人Jay Adams
so you'll have to decide whether you're
所以你必须决定你是否
gonna be on John MacArthur's side or
会在John MacArthur身边或者
you're going to be on Jay
你会在杰伊身上
site and not because he's the president
网站，而不是因为他是总统
of our school but I take John
我的学校，但我带约翰
MacArthur's position and I didn't get
麦克阿瑟的立场和我没有得到
paid to say that you see the issue in
付钱说你看到了这个问题
these two verses by the way there's the
这两节经文的方式还有的
issue mark 11:25 I already read so I
问题11:25我已经读过了，所以我
won't reread it you're by yourself you
不会重读你自己就是你自己
can forgive Luke 7 17 3 Jay Adams says
可以原谅Luke7 17 3 JayAdams说
be on your guard if your brother sins
如果你的兄弟犯了罪，请保持警惕
rebuke him if he repents forgive him so
责备他，如果他悔改，原谅他如此
he says you're under no obligation to
他说你没有义务
forgive unless the person repents now
原谅，除非这个人现在悔改
I'm going to you can read the quotes I'm
我要告诉你，我可以阅读引文
not going to take the time to read the
不打算花时间阅读
quotes because I have some other things
引用因为我还有其他一些东西
that I want to get to that I think are
我想要达到的目标
even more practical the two books are in
这两本书更加实用
the bibliography so if you want to study
参考书目所以如果你想学习
this issue a little bit more on your own
这个问题多一点你自己
you have the names of the books in your
你有自己的书名
bibliography I'm going to because this
参考书目我要去，因为这个
is the position I take I'm gonna talk a
是我采取的立场，我要谈谈
little bit more about John MacArthur's
关于约翰麦克阿瑟的更多信息
position I believe that it's possible
位置我相信这是可能的
even for big things to unilaterally
即使对于单方面的大事也是如此
forgive even if the other person doesn't
即使对方没有 原谅也要宽恕
repent mark 11:25 we've already read the
悔改11:25我们已经读过了
verse here's the way John MacArthur puts
这里是John MacArthur提出的方式
it in his book the freedom and power of
在他的书中，它的自由和力量
forgiveness he says if you are the only
宽恕他说，如果你是唯一的
injured party even if the offense was
受伤的一方，即使犯罪是
public and flagrant you may choose to
你可以选择公开和公然
forgive unilaterally I'm gonna close
单方面原谅我会结束
today with an illustration from my own
今天有我自己的插图
life of how that's possible but let me
生活如何可能，但让我
illustrate it with a biblical
用圣经来说明它
illustration turn to Genesis chapter 50
插图转向创世纪第50章
and you already know where I'm going if
你已经知道我要去哪里了
you know the book of Genesis you know
你知道创世记你知道
I'm going to the story of Joseph and in
我要讲述约瑟夫的故事
the story of Joseph we read this
约瑟夫的故事， 我们读到了这个
beginning with verse 15 their father had
与15节他们的父亲开始 了
just died and now the brothers who had
刚刚去世，现在的兄弟们
sinned so grievously against their
对他们的罪恶如此严重的犯罪
brother Joseph are afraid that now he's
兄弟约瑟夫害怕现在他是
going to take out vengeance after they
他们之后要去复仇
sold him into slavery and he says to
把他卖给奴隶，他说
them
他们
verse 15 when Joseph's brothers saw that
约瑟夫兄弟看到这一点时的第15节
their father was dead they said what if
他们的父亲死了他们说如果
Joseph should bear a grudge against us
约瑟夫应该对我们怀有怨恨
and pay us back in full for all the
并支付我们回到完全所有
wrong which we did to him so they sent a
我们对他做了错，所以他们发了一个
message to Joseph saying your father
约瑟夫说你父亲的消息
charged before he died saying thus you
在他去世之前被控告说你
shall say to Joseph please forgive I beg
请对约瑟夫说请原谅
you the transgression of your brothers
你犯了你兄弟的罪
and their sin for they did you wrong by
和他们的罪，因为他们错了你
the way there is nothing earlier in the
没有什么比这更早的方式了
book where they came and asked for
预订他们来的地方并要求
forgiveness there is absolutely no
宽恕绝对没有
repentance earlier in the book and now
在书的前面和现在悔改
please forgive the transgression of the
请原谅 的 罪过
servants of the god of your father and
你父亲和神的仆人
then Joseph wept when they spoke to him
然后约瑟夫在和他说话时哭了
his brothers also came and fell down
他的兄弟也来了，摔倒了
before him and said Behold we are your
在他面前说，看哪，我们是你的
servants and Joseph said to them do not
仆人和约瑟夫对他们说没有
be afraid for MI in God's place I'm not
害怕的MI在神的地方，我不
the judge often withholding forgiveness
法官经常拒绝原谅
can be a form of judgment I am playing
可以是我正在玩的一种判断形式
God I want to condemn this person by the
上帝， 我想谴责这个人
way that is also true of a critical
一种关键的方式也是如此
spirit towards others where we want to
对我们想要的其他人的精神
be the judge in the place of God
成为上帝之地的审判者
we want justice Joseph recognizes am I
我们想要正义约瑟夫认出我
in the place of God as for you you meant
在你的意思上代替上帝
evil against me but God meant it for
邪恶反对我，但上帝意味着它
good in order to bring about this
很好，以实现这一目标
present result to preserve many people
目前的结果是为了保护很多人
alive so therefore do not be afraid
所以活着所以不要害怕
he had already granted forgiveness
他已经给予了宽恕
earlier in the book he's here just
在书的前面，他就在这里
reaffirming that he had already forgiven
重申他已经原谅了
them I will provide for you and your
我会为你和你提供
little ones so he comforted them and
小家伙让他安慰他们
spoke kindly to them let's move on so we
亲切地同他们交谈，让我们继续前进，所以我们
don't get bogged down on that issue and
不要陷入这个问题
talk about what about the consequences
谈谈后果如何
just for a moment so I'm going to skip
只是片刻，所以我要跳过
past those quotes biblically we come up
过去那些引用圣经我们上来了
with kind of a paradox
有点悖论
sometimes mercy is given and sometimes
有时候会给予怜悯
there's consequences and I'll just
有后果，我会
remind you that all sin has consequences
提醒你，所有的罪都有后果
right all sin has consequences
对所有的罪都有后果
especially if the law is involved and
特别是如果法律涉及和
somebody may be for
有人可能是为了
but if laws have been broken there may
但如果法律被打破，可能会
be legal consequences that have to be
是必须的法律后果
followed through sometimes there's a
接下来有时会有一个
time for mercy sometimes there's a time
怜悯的时间有时会有一段时间
for consequences how do you determine
对于后果你如何确定
here's how I determine should I be
这是我如何确定我应该如何
giving mercy or should I hold them
给予怜悯或者我应该追究他们
accountable to the consequences I ask
对我要求的后果负责
myself the question what is in the best
我自己的问题是什么是最好的
interest of this person what is in the
这个人的兴趣在于什么
best interest of this person sometimes
有时这个人的最大利益
it's in their best interest to just be
这是他们的最佳利益只是
merciful and forget the consequences
仁慈而忘记后果
sometimes it's merciful or it's in the
有时它是仁慈的，或者它在
best interest of that person to hold
持有该人的最佳利益
them accountable and I'll give you a
他们负责任，我会给你一个
quick illustration of that a few years
那几年快速插图
ago or a number of years ago a student
以前或几年前的一个学生
stole about fourteen thousand dollars of
偷了大约一万四千美元
computer and media equipment from the
来自的计算机和媒体设备
Masters College to support a drug habit
大师学院支持吸毒习惯
now you can imagine that student didn't
现在你可以想象那个学生没有
last long at the Masters College they
他们在硕士学院上学很久
didn't know for other reasons he was
因为其他原因他不知道
asked to leave the Masters College you
要求离开大师学院你
can imagine he was a problem in the dorm
可以想象他是 宿舍里的一个问题
and they had worked with him for a as we
和他们与他 共事 的，因为我们
do with our students we really try to
与我们的学生一起努力
work with them and disciple them but he
与他们一起工作并训练他们，但他
wasn't responding so he was asked to
没有回应，所以他被要求
leave I became acquainted with him
离开我结识了他
through his parents and his parents
通过他的父母和他的父母
asked if I would try to work with him
问我是否愿意和他一起工作
well his conscience was really bothering
他的良心真的很烦
him and after about a year of counseling
他和大约一年的咨询后
him he finally confessed to me there's
他终于向我承认了
something that's really bothering my
一些真正困扰我的东西
conscience and I want to deal with this
良心，我想处理这个问题
and he confessed to me stealing this
他向我 承认 偷了这个
equipment well the master's college had
设备以及主人的大学有
already been reimbursed by their
已经由他们报销了
insurance company for this theft of
这家盗窃的保险公司
equipment well he confessed he said I'm
设备很好，他承认他说我
willing and it was I thought I was
愿意，我以为我是
seeing genuine repentance because part
看到真正的忏悔，因为部分
of repentance is there's fruit in
悔改是有果实的
keeping with repentance so as scripture
保持悔改，如经文
says and he was willing to bear the
说，他愿意忍受
consequences even if it meant I have to
后果，即使这意味着我必须
go to jail because I've got to get this
去监狱因为我必须得到这个
right between the Lord I've got to get
在主之间，我必须得到
this right with the Masters College so
这与马斯特学院的权利如此
making a long story short I arranged for
作出长话短说 我安排
him to meet with a representative from
他以满足 从代表
the administration from the Masters
来自大师的管理
College I had worked with him on how to
大学我和他一起工作过如何
make a confession he went through the
作忏悔他经历过
whole confession process
整个忏悔过程
he was forgiven but we had decided ahead
他被宽恕但我们已经决定了
of time because of the incredibly
因为令人难以置信的时间
undisciplined nature in which this
散漫的天性在此
student had demonstrated in his life he
学生在他的生活中证明了他
had a long-standing history of being
有着悠久的存在历史
incredibly undisciplined just the drug
只是药物令人难以置信的无纪律
lifestyle etc it would not be in his
生活方式等不会在他的生活中
best interest to just say you're free
最好的兴趣就是说你有空
from this fourteen thousand dollars we
从这一万四千美元我们
thought it would be a very good
认为这将是一个非常好的
discipline practice for him to have to
纪律的做法让他不得不
repay the school which he did he repaid
偿还他所偿还的学校
the school it turned into an incredible
学校变成了不可思议的
witnessing opportunity because then the
见证机会，因为那时
school was able to reimburse the
学校能够报销
insurance company how often does that
保险公司经常这样做
happen and they were able to tell the
发生了，他们能够告诉
insurance company why they were being
保险公司为什么会这样
reimbursed sometimes there's time it's a
报销有时会有时间
time for mercy sometimes there's a time
怜悯的时间有时会有一段时间
for consequences and you have to
对于后果，你必须
determine what is I believe that the
确定什么是我 相信
principle there is what is in the best
原则是什么是最好的
interest of this person now over it
现在对这个人的兴趣
let's finish with this overcoming
让我们完成这个克服
unforgiveness and rebuilding
不宽恕和重建
relationships I'm not going to go to the
关系我不打算去
passage we've already referred to this
通过我们已经提到过这个
passage and this principle realize that
通过，这个原则实现了这一点
unforgiveness will separate you from God
不宽恕会使你与上帝隔绝
and could state something about your
并可以陈述一些关于你的事情
salvation
救恩
let me just read Matthew 18 verse 35
让我读一下马太福音18章35节
please read Matthew 18 sometime it's an
请阅读马太福音18 某个时候它是一个
incredible passage about forgiveness
关于宽恕的令人难以置信的段落
chap verses 21 through 35 about how the
第21节到第35节关于如何进行
king forgave an incredibly large debt
国王原谅了巨大的债务
but then the person who was forgiven
但后来被宽恕的人
held the person who owed them money was
举行欠他们钱的人是
very harsh and judgmental with them when
当他们非常苛刻和评判时
when the King found it out the King said
当国王发现它时，国王说
in verse 34 and his Lord moved with
在第34节，他的主移动了
anger handed him over to the torturers
愤怒把他交给了拷打者
until he should repay all that was owed
直到他应该偿还所欠的一切
him so shall my Heavenly Father also do
我的天父也应如此
to you if each of you does not forgive
如果你们每个人都不原谅你
his brother from your heart that raises
他的兄弟从你的心里抬起来
interesting theological questions I
有趣的神学问题我
believe that the key to this would be
相信这将是关键
lack of forgiveness could state
缺乏宽恕可以说明
something about the reality of your
关于你的现实的一些事情
salvation if a person is unwilling to
如果一个人不愿意拯救
forgive how could we say doesn't it
原谅我们怎么能说不呢
sound like a I mean it would be
听起来像是我的意思
incredibly paradoxical for a person to
令人难以置信的矛盾一个人
say I have been forgiven by God but I
说我被上帝宽恕但是我
can't forgive you that it that is a
不能原谅你，这是一个
paradox that scripture just can't even
悖论，经文甚至不能
imagine that a person would be forgiving
想象一下，一个人 是宽容
their eternal sin but then cannot grant
他们永恒的罪，但后来不能给予
forgiveness to others if you want to
如果你愿意，可以宽恕别人
look at other passages on this Matthew
看看这个马太的其他段落
chapter 6 the Lord's Prayer verses 14
第六章 主祷文第14节
and 15 teach the exact same thing
和15 教导完全相同的事情
homework that I've done with people that
我和那些人做过的功课
are struggling with forgiveness is from
正在努力宽恕来自
Matthew 18 often and I asked them to
马太福音18经常和我一起问他们
make a list of how they've sinned
列出他们是如何犯罪的
against God and then I asked them to
反对上帝然后我问他们
compare how do your sins compare to the
比较你的罪行与罪恶的比较
sins of blank against you and then this
对你而言这是空白的罪
is the clincher question how would you
是硬道理的问题你会如何
feel if God treated your sins the way
感觉如果上帝对待你的罪的方式
you're treating blanks sins that's the
你正在处理空白的罪行
clincher question and I've seen a lot of
紧张的问题，我已经看到了很多
good repentance take place once they
他们一旦悔改就会发生
start to think about the answer to that
开始思考这个问题的答案
question so realize that unforgiveness
问题所以要意识到不宽恕
will separate you from God and could
将你与上帝分开， 并且可以
state something about the true nature of
陈述一些关于真实性质的东西
your salvation secondly overcoming
你的救赎其次是克服
unforgiveness and rebuilding
不宽恕和重建
relationships renounce sinful attitudes
关系放弃了罪恶的态度
and unrealistic expectations here's some
这里有一些不切实际的期望
of the sinful attitudes and unrealistic
罪恶的态度和不切实际的态度
expectations that just would not be
预期就不会成为
biblical expecting the offender to earn
圣经期待罪犯赚钱
or deserve forgiveness God doesn't do
还是值得宽恕上帝不这样做
that with you desire to punish the
那与你想要惩罚的
offender God doesn't do that with you
罪犯上帝不会和你这样做
demanding a guarantee that this won't
要求保证不会这样做
happen again here's just a little
再次发生这里只是一点点
counseling hint that I've wondered about
咨询暗示我一直在想
as I've seen people struggling with
因为我见过人们疲于应付
forgiveness I've wondered if it's a way
宽恕我想知道这是不是一种方式
to stay in control of the situation I
控制局势我
don't want to release this because as
不想发布这个因为as
soon as I released this I'm not in
我发布此消息后，我就不在了
control of the situation or here
控制情况还是在这里
another heart theme that could be coming
另一个可能即将到来的心脏主题
out I want justice I demand justice and
我想要正义我要求正义和
clinging to the bitterness in my heart
紧紧抓住我心中的苦涩
is my way of getting justice somebody is
是我获得正义的方式
very wisely said that bitterness is the
非常明智地说，苦涩就是
poison
毒
we drank hoping it will kill someone
我们喝酒希望它能杀死某人
else isn't it a demand for justice often
否则不是经常要求正义
and instead of trusting God's justice
而不是相信神的公义
that he will make all things right
他会把一切都做对
Romans chapter 12 that he's the one that
罗马书第12章说他是那个人
will get vengeance God is a God of
会报复上帝是上帝的
perfect justice and then draw on God's
完美的正义，然后借鉴上帝的
strength obviously and then practice the
力量明显然后练习
reconciliation and replacement principle
和解与替代原则
this is a beautiful principle and I'm
这是一个美丽的原则，我
gonna finish with an illustration of how
最后将以如何说明
this has worked in my own life so
这在我自己的生活工作得
reconciliation would mean this and you
和解意味着这和你
can think through the implications for
可以思考其影响
your own life we want to be restored to
我们希望自己的生活 恢复到
the person so reconciliation to God
这个人如此与上帝和好
means that were restored to the
意味着恢复了
condition before the conflict arose if
如果发生冲突之前的条件
not better we're actually restored to a
不是更好，我们实际上恢复了一个
better position this is mind-boggling
更好的位置这是令人难以置信的
theology were restored in Christ to a
神学在基督里恢复了
better position than Adam had before the
比亚当之前更好的位置
fall because we're now in Christ it's
因为我们现在在基督里了
absolutely mind-boggling boggling
绝对让人难以置信
theology or Deus this is a subjective
神学或Deus这是一个主观的
one and I would just warn you about
一个，我会警告你
being careful about the subjectivity of
小心的主观性
this you sense the barriers are gone
你觉得障碍已经消失了
between you and the other person for or
你和另一个人之间或
this is one that I found to be helpful
这是我发现有用的一个
reconciliation would mean that there's a
和解意味着有一个
deeper and insert the word or a deeper
更深入，插入或更深入的单词
or more realistic relationship now maybe
或者现在可能更现实的关系
you realize I've heard of people getting
你意识到我听说有人得到了
reconciled but their friendship just
他们的友谊只是和解了
isn't the same as it was and I'm some of
是不一样的，我是一些
my children that have got been
我的孩子们一直都是
reconciled with broken in broken
和破碎的和解
friendships they realized wow we had
友谊他们意识到我们有哇
expectations for this friendship that
对这种友谊的期望
just weren't realistic now we have a
现在我们有一个不太现实
more realistic
更现实
but it doesn't have all those pressures
但它并没有那么多压力
involved in all those unrealistic
参与所有那些不切实际的事情
expectations but they're reconciled with
期望， 但他们是和睦相处的
one another so you work on reconceive
彼此， 所以你努力重新思考
'no ii silly ation you're seeing what
“没有愚蠢的话，你看到了什么
reconciliation means how do you read
和解意味着你如何阅读
we're asking the question how do you
我们问的问你怎么样
rebuild the relationship and then you
重建关系，然后你
practice the replacement principle in
实践中的替代原则
conclusion here I'm gonna remember put
结论在这里我会记得放
off the old man be renewed in the spirit
老人在精神上得到了更新
of the mind and put on the new man I'm
心灵，并把我的新男人穿上
gonna practice in each area you see in
要在你看到的 每个区域练习
your notes in my thought life in my
在我的思想生活中你的笔记
words in my deeds and in my inner person
在我的行为和内心的人
replacing putting off being renewed and
取代推迟更新和
putting on in my relationship with this
穿上我与此的关系
person and I'm telling you this can be a
那个人，我告诉你这可能是一个
battle it might have to happen every 30
战斗它可能每30年发生一次
seconds for a while as you're trying
你正在尝试的一段时间
you're telling yourself I released them
你告诉自己我发布了它们
from that and I said I made a promise I
从那以后我说我做了一个承诺
am NOT going to dwell on this now let me
我现在不要再纠缠于此了
give you a closing illustration mm-hmm
给你一个关闭插图mm-hmm
and I have a great picture here to
我有一个伟大的图片在这里
finish with I like studying the American
我最喜欢研究美国人
Civil War so I've got a civil war
内战所以我有一个内战
picture for you they're expect a battle
图片给你他们期待一场战斗
here's the closing illustration of the
这是关闭的插图
reconciliation and replacement principle
和解与替代原则
as I told you before my dad was a pastor
就像我爸爸做牧师之前告诉过你的那样
and I grew up I was unfortunately the
我长大了不幸的是
stereotypical preacher's kid and in my
陈规定型传教士的孩子和我的孩子
teenage years I was the type of kid that
十几岁的时候， 我是那种孩子
you would warn your kids not to hang
你会警告你的孩子不要挂
around so I was the poster boy for
所以我是那个海报男孩
rebellion and in my teenage years I
叛乱和我十几岁的时候
absolutely despised my father hated him
绝对鄙视我的父亲恨他
to the point of plotting murder in my
到我的谋杀谋杀谋杀的地步
mind how I could get rid of him I do not
记住我怎么能摆脱他我没有
believe I was saved even though I had
相信即使我有，我也得救了
prayed a prayer at age five I believe
我相信在五岁时祈祷
that I repented at age 17 and one of the
我在17岁时悔改，其中一个
first things that happened in my life
我生命中发生的第一件事
about two weeks into my new relationship
我的新关系大约两周了
with the Lord I was absolutely miserable
与主我是绝对悲惨的
I repented came to faith in Christ about
我悔改了，相信基督
two weeks in I was under deep conviction
在我的两个星期里，我深信不疑
and about my relationship with my father
以及我与父亲的 关系
I hadn't heard any sermons the Holy
我没有听过任何布道神圣
Spirit just started working on my inner
精神刚刚开始在我的内心努力
person that I needed to go get
我需要去的人
reconciled with my father I was just
与我父亲和解我是公正的
extremely hateful and bitter my dad was
我爸爸非常讨厌和痛苦
a World War 2 veteran I got to travel
我要去旅行的第二次世界大战的老兵
when we were in Europe this past spring
今年春天我们在欧洲的时候
I got to travel to some of the
我去了一些旅行
battlefields where my dad fought and
我父亲战斗的战场
that was absolutely amazing that I got
这是绝对惊人的，我得到了
to do that I used to call my father
为此， 我曾经打电话给我父亲
Hitler now can you imagine how my dad
希特勒现在可以想象我父亲是怎么回事
took that being a World War two veteran
这是第二次世界大战的老将
that fought under Patton in the Third
在第三局中以巴顿战斗
Army there had to be an incredible
军队必须是一个不可思议的
insult knife into his heart to have his
侮辱刀进入他的心里有他的
son call him Hitler so I was very very
儿子叫他希特勒所以我非常非常
bitter at my father and what I did to
对我父亲的苦涩和我的所作所为
practice Ephesians 4:31 and 32 I was
以弗所书4:31和32我曾经
sitting in a biblical counseling class
坐在圣经辅导班
back in the 1970s at Washington Bible
早在20世纪70年代的华盛顿圣经
College in Washington DC and I had a
华盛顿特区的大学 和我有一个
real biblical counseling class
真正的圣经辅导班
introduction to biblical counseling and
介绍圣经辅导和
we were going through Ephesians 4:31 and
我们正在经历以弗所书4:31和
32 I was tired of the bitterness it was
我厌倦了它的苦涩
eating me up on the inside I really
我真的在里面吃我
wanted to get reconciled with my father
希望得到和解与我的父亲
so I went through a process of about two
所以我经历了大约两个人 的过程
weeks of trying to think of anything I
试图想什么星期中， 我
could think of that my father had done
可以想到我父亲做过的事
that I thought to sin against me and I
我以为我和我犯了罪
released it I was sending it away I was
释放它我发送它我是
trying to practice based upon my new
试图根据我的新做法练习
relationship with Jesus Christ I've been
与耶稣基督的关系我一直都是
forgiven so much in Christ and I have so
我在基督里得到了如此多的宽恕
much sin in Christ who am I to hold all
在基督里犯了很多罪，我要掌握一切
this stuff against my father and I
这件事反对我父亲和我
practiced releasing it against my father
练习释放它对我的父亲
and then it would come right back up
然后它会立即回来
and I would say nope I released that I
而且我会说不，我释放了我
am NOT gonna think about that I'm
我不会想到我
sending that away I'm gonna nail it to
发送它我会指出它
the cross based upon what Christ has
基于基督所拥有的十字架
done for me and then even though it was
为我完成，然后即使它是
very difficult and thought word deed
非常困难和思想的单词行为
desires remember my desire now is I love
欲望记住我的愿望现在是我的爱
Jesus Christ
耶稣基督
he's my Lord I want to do what my Lord
他是我的主我想做我的主
desires of me so Lord for you I'm gonna
我的欲望所以主啊，我要去
release my dad of all these offenses
释放我父亲所有这些罪行
that I thought that he had against me
我认为他反对我
so I'm gonna start thinking positive
所以我会开始积极思考
thoughts about my dad Philippians 4:8
关于我父亲腓立比书4：8的想法
and I came up with things to be thankful
我想出了 值得感恩的事情
for and I would pray things that I was
因为我会祈祷我的事情
thankful for for my father I at first it
我起初感谢我的父亲
was extremely difficult but I went to
非常困难， 但我去了
our little bookstore and bought him
我们的小书店买了他
cards and I bought him a card and I try
卡片，我给他买了一张卡，我试试
to send him thank-you cards for things
给他发送感谢卡的东西
that I appreciated about him then I
那时我对他表示赞赏
called him so you see that's thought
叫他，所以你看到了这个想法
then you see word and I was praying for
然后你看到了我正在祈祷的话语
him daily it's hard to be bitter at a
他每天都很难受苦
person you're praying for so I was
你正在祈祷的人，所以我是
praying for God's blessing on his
祈求上帝的祝福上他
ministry etc etc then in Word I called
部等等然后在Word中我打电话给
him and asked him for advice about
他，问他有关的建议
something this was absolutely shocking
这绝对令人震惊
to my father I mean I remember the
对我的父亲， 我的意思是我记得
stunned silence on the phone when my dad
我父亲打电话时沉默的电话
when I said dad I need your advice about
当我说，爸爸，我需要你的意见左右
something this was a first in our
这是我们的第一件事
relationship so in thought in Word
在思想中的关系
indeed when I got home I tried to be
事实上，当我回到家时，我试图做到
respectful I did chores around the house
恭敬地， 我在家里做了家务
like I had never done before you know
就像我从来没有做过之后才知道
what happened in about two month period
在大约两个月的时间里发生了什么
of time the bitterness was gone from my
时间的苦涩从我的
soul I had sent it away nailed it to the
我送它的灵魂钉在了它上面
cross and I had practiced rebuilding my
十字架，我练习重建我的
relationship from my perspective with my
我的观点与我的关系
father that turned into a wonderful
父亲变成了一个美妙的人
relationship by the way my dad just
顺便说一下我爸刚关系
passed away a little over a year ago
去世略高于 一 年前
he's with the Lord now and we had many
他现在与主同在，我们有许多人
wonderful years of relationship after
美好的岁月关系之后
those extremely rocky years in in high
那些极其岩石几年在高
school I hope you think more about
学校我希望你多考虑一下
forgiveness
饶恕
biblically there's so much more that we
圣经上我们还有更多
could say the book that I would
可以说我会这本书
recommend for your edification for your
为您推荐的熏陶你
soul is the freedom and power of
灵魂是自由和力量
forgiveness by John MacArthur I think
我认为约翰麦克阿瑟的宽恕
you would find it not only theologically
你会发现它不仅仅是神学上的
stimulating but you'd find it really
刺激，但你真的发现它
good soul food
好心灵的食物
you
您